

PIERRE BOERKOEL

Year 3, Computer Science
778-989-3206; pierreboerkoel@gmail.com

Technical Skills & Projects

Computer Languages: Java, Racket

Ruby on Rails (May 2018): Followed a tutorial by Bruno Boehm for the creation of a partially-complete Ruby on Rails blog app deployed with Heroku. The tutorial involved work with Terminal, git, Bootstrap, HTML and Ruby.

Wordpress (May 2018): Created a website for Vancouver Second Mile Society with Wordpress using Amazon Web Services: http://18.204.201.94/ (work in progress).

BCS Hackathon (March 2018): Worked with three others to create a car-pooling application in Java. Due to time constraints, followed a tutorial to create a locally hosted chatbot with the Microsoft Bot Builder SDK for Node.js instead of the car-pooling application.

Java Project (March 2018): Worked on implementation of both the backend and frontend of a TransLink application for Android. This involved extensive JUnit testing, parsing of JSON objects, implementation of various methods, and work with the TransLink API.

Work Experience

Research Assistant, Kermode Lab, Simon Fraser University

May 2015-September 2017

- Expressed recombinant human enzymes in plant cells to discover potential drug candidates to treat lysosomal storage disorders. Poster presentation on this topic.
- Determined the genes underlying seed dormancy and germination in Yellow Cedar. Co-authoring a paper on this topic.
- Attended the Canadian Glycomics Network AGM & Symposium (Summer 2016) and a conference hosted by the International Society for Seed Science (Summer 2016).

Franchise Owner, Student Works Painting

September 2013-December 2014

• Produced approx. \$65K in work and was responsible for hiring employees, managing employees, advertising the business, signing clients, running job sites, and payroll.

Assistant Gardener, Parsley and Sage Gardening Works

April 2011-August 2014

• Responsible for tending to the gardens of 3 houses. Collected payment, installed a new lawn, and did minor landscaping.

Restaurant Worker, McDonalds

December 2009-August 2012

• Responsible for preparing orders, cooking food, cleaning, and stocking materials.

Volunteer Experience

Social Events Coordinator, Vancouver Coastal Health

January 2018-present

• Plan activities for ECU patients and help foster an open and caring environment.

Computer Services, Continental Seniors Centre

September 2017-present

• Maintain computer equipment at the centre and help underprivileged seniors with computer related needs.

Mentor, KidStart (PLEA BC)

September 2016-present

• Meet up weekly with a youth in Vancouver to help him overcome his agoraphobia.

Farm Manager, Mamaki Farms (Hawaii, USA)

December 2015-present (1 month/year)

- Look after livestock, mow grass, and care for gardens and various fruit trees.
- Planned and executed renovations including retiling a floor, painting and staining, installation of baseboards, doors, closets and bathroom amenities.

Education

University of British Columbia

Vancouver, BC

Bachelor of Computer Science, 3rd year

September 2017-May 2020

Bachelor of Science, Major in Biology

September 2012-May 2017

Graduated with Distinction

Awards

UBC English Department David Macaree Prize (\$600)	2018
NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award (\$4500)	2017
NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award (\$4500)	2016
Canadian Glycomics Network Summer Award for Undergraduates (\$4500)	2016
NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award (\$4500)	2015

Activities

Kitsilano Handball League

May 2017-April 2018 (4 months/year)

• Play goalie and forward. Help with set-up and clean-up. Referee and score-keep.

BC Touch Football

April 2017-present (4 months/year)

Played wide receiver, slot receiver, and corner. Placed third in the league.

UBC Intramural Football (tier 1)

September 2014-April 2017

• Played receiver, quarterback, and safety. Consistently placed first in the league.

Pierre Boerkoel Page 2